Finding Aid for Charlotte Langlands papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charlotte Langlands papers, 1885-1987 1890-1945
Langlands, Charlotte
1.4 linear feet including 1 oversize box
2013123 Aa2
Papers of Charlotte Langlands (1927-), member of Collegiate Sorosis. It includes records of Collegiate Sorosis, photographs, scrapbooks, and books. The collection also contains items from Langlands' first husband, Thomas Kuzma, that relate to his friendship with Tom Harmon.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Charlotte Langlands (Donor No. 10926 ) in May, 2013
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charlotte (Leach) Langlands was born in 1926 in Ohio to Charlotte Cossitt Leach and Sagito J. Leach. She married University of Michigan football player Thomas (Tom) G. Kuzma (1922-1996) on August 9, 1947 in Ashtabula, Ohio. Langlands was a member of the Collegiate Sorosis class of 1948. She officially graduated in August 1973. Langland substitute taught in Bloomfield. From April 1978 onwards, she was involved in the revival of the Sorosis active chapter. In 2006 she married Robert Langlands in Florida.
The bulk of the collection contains photographs and records of Collegiate Sorosis. In addition, there are photographs and items related to Tom Kuzma and his friendship with Tom Harmon. The collection is divided into two series: Collegiate Sorosis and Thomas Kuzma.
Subjects:
Langlands, Charlotte.; Harmon, Tom, 1919-1990.; Kuzma, Tom G., 1922-1996.; Collegiate Sorosis (University of Michigan); Fraternities and sororities.
Genre Terms:
Group portraits.; Photographs.
- Collegiate Sorosis
  Collegiate Sorosis series mainly consists of photographs ranging from its founding to 1972. An undated photo album with a collection of photographs that may have been taken in the early 1900s. Many of the photographs within the series are labeled with names and dates. Sorosis records include correspondence, training materials, histories of the organization, constitution and by-laws, and notes. Business records include invoices, deeds, account books, construction plans and blueprints for the sorority's home (Collegiate Sorosis is reportedly the first sorority to build and have its own home). Correspondence includes letters written by two of the charter members that announce their resignation from their old sororities. The series also includes correspondence from the New York Sorosis chapter, who served as inspiration to the founders. There are 7 member directories, some of which contain short biographies of the alumni. The outsize box contains more photographs of Collegiate Sorosis and one photograph of the University of Michigan Engineering Class of 1917 (of which her father was a member).
  - Collegiate Sorosis records, 1885--1987 (Box 1)
    - Business records
      - Contractors (Box 1)
      - Property (Box 1)
    - Constitution and by-laws (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Fundraising (Box 1)
    - History (Box 1)
  - Guestbook, 1909-1921 (Box 1)
  - Guestbook, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Member directories
    - 1911, 1926, 1936, 1948, 1953, 1969, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (outsize), 1886-972 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1892-1956, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Photo album, undated and ca. 1900-1910 (Box 1)
- Thomas Kuzma
  The Thomas Kuzma series contains photographs, a journal article, a wedding invitation, and signed book. Kuzma and Tom Harmon (inducted into Michigan Football Legends in September 2013) both grew up in Gary, Indiana and became friends while they played football together. The bulk of the series focuses on that friendship. Of particular interest within the series is a signed photograph of Harmon in his football uniform and an autographed copy of Harmon's 1944 book,Pilots Also Play. There is also an invitation to Harmon's wedding. In addition, there is a signed photograph of University of Michigan football coach Fritz Crisler.
  - Pilots also Play by Tom Harmon, 1944 (Box 1)
    (autographed by author)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
Related Collections
The Bentley Historical Library houses the Collegiate Sorosis (University of Michigan) Records, 1886--1991. The collection contains the history of the sorority, minutes of meetings, records of Sorosis House, scrapbooks, printed matter, and photographs. The finding aid can be found online with the following URL:
The Bentley also has a vertical file (FImu/F47) about the sorority. Within a separate collection of scrapbooks, entitled "Student Scrapbooks: The Michigan Experience," are two scrapbooks that contain items relating to Collegiate Sorosis. One of the scrapbooks was created by Josephine Marie Hayden Satterthwaite and the other was by Louise Potter.